Hamid Ghader

hamid.ghader@live.com linkedin.com/in/hghader

ABOUT

I am an experienced software engineer with over 14 years of employment record, worked as a Technical Lead and as a Software Developer. I have been involved in numerous successful projects, responsible for a variety of duties, including providing technical advice, architecting, designing, and coding software systems.

I am a proficient coder in several programming languages encompassing the entire stack from writing robust and efficient back-ends to implementing clear and consistent front-ends. I am particularly interested in designing and implementing cloud-native distributed systems in ♥ Go ♥ Programming Language.

I am familiar with modern application architectures such as Microservices, Event Sourcing and CQRS, MVC, Reactive Programming, and Domain-Driven Design.

SKILLS

Languages

Go C# JavaScript/TypeScript Visual Basic

Databases

SQL Server Oracle MongoDB Elasticsearch Redis etcd

Messaging

Kafka NATS gRPC Protocol Buffers JSON XML

Operations

AWS Kubernetes Docker CI/CD Git Terraform Prometheus

Web

ASP.NET (WebForms/MVC) HTML CSS LESS SASS Chrome Extensions Selenium/WebDriver

EXPERIENCE

Mar 2018 - Present, Software Engineer, Utility Warehouse (London, UK)

 Building Event Sourced Microservices using Go, Kafka, Protocol Buffers, and gRPC. Running in Kubernetes and AWS.

2014-2018, Technical Lead, Geeks Ltd (London, UK)

- · Successfully delivered numerous mission-critical client projects on time and on budget.
- In charge of technical direction of projects, transforming client requirements to technical concepts, making architectural and design decisions, and reporting to directors.
- Interacted with PMs and BAs in UX design/wireframing process, project/sprint planning, providing estimations, and task delegation.
- Mentoring developers, pair programming, code review, sharing knowledge, and applying best practices (Design Patterns, SOLID, KISS, and DRY).

2010-2013, Senior Software Developer, Geeks Ltd (London, UK)

- Involved in day-to-day coding, debugging, testing, deployment, and maintenance of client projects.
- Contributed to company's growth both individually and as part of team by great performance and training other developers.

2009, Senior Software Developer, Saman Electronic Payment (Tehran, Iran)

- Implemented a Windows Service to replicate large volume of financial transactions from Oracle to SQL Server for reporting purposes.
- Developed a web application to deliver a variety of financial reports to merchants.

2005-2008, Software Developer, Nofasoft (Tehran, Iran)

- Provided a software solution to Cutting Stock Problem (CSP) using Genetic Algorithms, used by aluminium door and window makers to minimise their cutting waste.
- Pleased to offer the company my own developed O/R Mapping tool.

2004, Software Developer, Mahfa Co (Tehran, Iran)

 Re-developed legacy MS Access accounting and stock management systems using C# and SQL Server. Increased maintainability by improving object-oriented and relational model design.

EDUCATION

MSc Information Systems Development

2010-2011, London Metropolitan University (London, UK)

BSc Applied Computer Software

• 2004-2007, Shamsipour Institute of Technology (Tehran, Iran)

Last update: March 2019

EOF